Yogesh Gupta

LinkedIn: vogesh-gupta-117495169

Portfolio: https://yogeshportfolio.vercel.app/ Github: https://github.com/yogesh8633

New Delhi, India

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seniors Solutions Architect at OCPL TECH. I have more than 1.5 years of experience in designing and development of web applications. Expertise in **full-stack development** and **project management**

HIGHLIGHTS

Key Early Contributor at OCPL:

Joined as the second employee at OCPL and played a pivotal role in the company's growth from its inception. Contributed to expanding the client base to over 10+ CRM and website clients and helped grow the team to more than 30 members.

- Leadership experience in Celect Placement Cell at Ramanujan College from 2021-22
- **Awarded** with PK kaul Memorial Scholarship in First Year of College
- Awarded with prize money for being FIRST in First Year Of College
- C/C++

Email: yogesh9711@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 9711708633

- Javascript
- NodeJS
- ReactJS
- Bootstrap
- Framer Motion
- SASS, CSS
- POSTMAN
- VS Code
- Dapps
- Blockchain
- Github, Gitlab
- IPFS
- MongoDB, SQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

OCPL TECH | Senior Solutions Architect

Delhi May 2023 - present

- Lead developer and solution designer for complex projects
- My responsibilities included designing solutions for the projects. Collaborating with the team of developers. I ensured the successful implementation of the proposed solutions.
- From Backend to Frontend, from client meetings to delivery. I have handled each and every thing here.
- **Developed** new features and enhancements in **fast-paced environments**
- Researched and identified software solutions to meet customer needs and objectives.
- Conducted code reviews to maintain quality and performance standards

OCPL TECH | Frontend Developer

Delhi *Mar 2023 - May 2023*

- Worked as a developer to built blockchain based products for the company, Learnt above IPFS and overview
 of blockchain.
- Tech Stack : ReactJS, CSS, IPFS, Blockchain.
- Collaborated with backend developers to ensure seamless integration of frontend and backend components.
- Developed reusable components for scalability
- worked with backend developers to implement integrations with server side technologies.

Web Developer | Hatke Attire

Delhi Sept 2021 - Nov 2021

- Proficient in developing responsive, cross browser compatible websites
- Excellent communications and collaboration skills with other developers and non technical staff.
- Experienced in integrating with RESTful APIs and backend Services

EDUCATION

Ramanujan College, Delhi University
Bachelor Degree Software Development, CGPA: 9.05

2019-2022

Delhi

M.D.H International School

XII; Percentage: 86%

Delhi June 2018